Robin Moussu

Back-end developer specialization in optimization

Curious, ready to push changes, autonomous and volunteer, I am someone who love learning and know how to invest myself (especially in mastering my tools). High performance back-ends development, algorithms and optimizations are subjects that I love the most in my work. Since a bit more than two years, I discovered myself a passion for Rust and I had the chance to use it professionally. It's a technology that I'd like to use again in the future.

Competences

Languages Rust, C++, shell, C, exposure to python, scala, SML, asm

Utils git, Linux, exposure to gcc, clang, valgrind, perf, Doxygen

Metodology OOP, functional programming

English Daily usage, C1 level Bulats: 79 (2014), Toeic: 740 (2013)

Professional experience

2021—present Back-end software developer, exploration and UX 1 years Silvaco (full remote, then partially on site), Grenoble C++, html, css, js

Prototyping of a query language specialized in data extraction from netlists.

Improvements in the visualization of analysis.

I helped my team migrate to git (formation and individual training).

2019–2020 Back-end software developer, specialized in optimizations 1 years

Astek (for the client Naver, on-site, then full remote), Grenoble Rust, python

Optimizations and improvements of the generation of tours intended to be run.

Successful rewrite of the project in Rust

2016–2019 Back-end software developer

3 years

Astek (for the client Amadeus, on-site), Nice C++, scala, shell Participation in various projects of PIO (Pricing Integration and Orchestration). Set-up and animation of weekly sessions of knowledge sharing.

2016 End of study internship

6 month

MathWorks (on Polyspace software), Grenoble C++, SML Alias analysis and context splitting: amelioration of the static analysis speed and precision of C codebase using function pointers.

Formation

2013–2016 **Grenoble INP**, Grenoble, Phelma then Ensimag BAC +5 Specialization in system and embedded software

2011–2013 **DUT GEII**, Grenoble, IUT 1 BAC +2

2010 Baccalauréat S, Gap, Lycée Dominique Villars (with honors)

Electronic engineering and industrial data processing